<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<news><type>stampa</type><title>Leonardo and Avioane Craiova sign technological and industrial cooperation agreement for current and future aeronautical programmes</title><subtitle /><author /><date>Paris,  18 giugno 2025 15:28</date><content>At the Paris Air Show, Leonardo and Avioane Craiova announced the signing of a
“Technological and Industrial Cooperation Agreement”, marking a significant step forward in strengthening the industrial collaboration between the two companies.

The agreement covers several areas of potential cooperation, with a primary focus on Leonardo’s C-27J Spartan, and the M-345 and M-346 Integrated Training Systems (ITS), including the localization in Romania of activities related to the C-27J avionic upgrade program, maintenance and logistics, repairs and personnel training.

Avioane Craiova is intended to be deeply involved in the current avionic upgrade program of the seven C-27J Spartan fleet successfully operated by the Romanian Air Force since 2010. This important modernization program, which encompasses new state-of-the-art systems integration, as well as training activities, would guarantee a significant industrial return, paving the path also for future industrial programs, aimed at progressively building a reliable C-27J regional industrial hub in Avioane Craiova.

The Leonardo and Avioane Craiova agreement would also enable further perspectives, aimed at commonly building a complex proposal, thereby enabling the Romanian Air Force to integrate a new paradigm for pilots training, based on the M-345 and M-346 Integrated Training System. This approach would facilitate the establishment of new local maintenance, sub-assembly, logistic and support capabilities, contributing to the long-term sustainability of the Romanian Air Force’s fleet. This would also foster the growth of Romania’s defense industrial base, opening new opportunities for technological cooperation, skills development, and high-value employment in Romania.

As the Romanian Air Force is planning the entry into service of F-35 5th generation fighters, which will complement the growing fleet of F-16s, the Integrated Training System, based on the M-345 and M-346, represents a proven solution for the task. It facilitates the transition to the operational status requested by evolving challenging threats, guaranteeing the effectiveness and readiness that a NATO operator, like the Romanian Air Force, requires.</content></news>