<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<news><type>stampa</type><title>Leonardo and Bombardier Defense sign MoU to assess and target new opportunities in the global maritime MMA market</title><subtitle /><author /><date>Paris,  17 giugno 2025 09:30</date><content>At the Paris Air Show Leonardo and Bombardier Defense announced they’re entering into a collaboration phase to explore new opportunities in the Maritime MMA (Multi-Mission Aircraft) capability market. The parties signed a non-exclusive Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) intended to evaluate the possibility to respond to the growing demand for this wide range of airborne capabilities by integrating selected Leonardo systems into the Bombardier Global 6500 twin-engine jet platform. This would allow the parties to transform the aircraft into a next-generation Maritime MMA system targeting stringent market requirements. 
 
The value proposition thus stems from a fusion of Leonardo’s top-tier ATOS mission system with multi-mission versatility, integrating Leonardo’s customizable mission sensors, and installed upon Bombardier’s platform delivering a comprehensive, integrated Surveillance solution. This might lead to the crafting of a specialized product offering, leveraging the integration of state-of-the-art acoustic, mission systems, and sensors for the task. 
 
Leonardo offers unparalleled expertise in mission systems, sensors, and self-protection equipment, embedded into proprietary and non-proprietary platforms for both fixed and rotary wing operations, giving forces in the field a clear operational advantage, alongside superior information to support decision-making and intervention throughout the entire chain of command. With a history of delivering more than 500 specialized aircraft for a variety of missions in defence, security and humanitarian operations, Bombardier Defense brings exceptional expertise and a high-performing platform essential for modern forces’ multi-mission needs. Bombardier’s proven and versatile Global 6500* aircraft combined with Leonardo’s world-class mission systems are perfectly aligned to meet operational demands of discerning users. 

*Bombardier, Bombardier Defense, Global and Global 6500 are registered or unregistered trademarks of Bombardier Inc. or its subsidiaries.

 </content></news>