<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<news><type>stampa</type><title>Leonardo and Weststar launch major government rotorcraft expansion and modernization programme in Malaysia with a total requirement for 28 helicopters</title><subtitle /><author /><date>Langkawi,  20 maggio 2025 11:25</date><content>At Langkawi International Maritime and Aerospace Exhibition - LIMA, Leonardo and long-established partner Weststar Aviation Services (Weststar) of Malaysia celebrated today the launch of the most significant Government helicopter fleet expansion and modernization program ever for the manufacturer in the country, intended to meet a wide range of national requirements for defence, security and the support of communities. Within the framework of this programme, Weststar foresees the delivery of up to 28 helicopters of various types, in a mix of firm orders and options, most of them between 2026 and 2027. Weststar will lease the aircraft to the Malaysian Government for 15 years, with dedicated localized support and training services to the operator.

The programme represents a significant growth of Leonardo Helicopters’ presence among several Malaysian military, homeland security. and public service operators. It includes various types for the Royal Malaysian Police and Bomba for law enforcement, utility, transport, firefighting, EMS/SAR, and disaster relief missions. Among the different models, the programme also comprises AW149 helicopters for the Royal Malaysian Air Force and the Royal Malaysian Army, for Combat Search and Rescue and utility applications, marking the entrance of the latest generation multirole military helicopter in Malaysia and further growing the success of the type among defence operators in the international market.

Leonardo continues to strengthen its role in the Malaysian helicopter market. Its vision is to position the country at the core of its expansion strategy and as a regional champion for rotorcraft and greater capabilities in the aerospace sector. Building on a long-standing presence and partnerships with Malaysian players, Leonardo is reinforcing its commitment with investments, localizing more industrial activities, and developing opportunities for innovation.

With a regional hub for customer support and training near Kuala Lumpur, Leonardo is the only helicopter Training Academy outside its home markets. Over the years, Leonardo has seen hundreds of helicopters perform missions such as utility, homeland security, law enforcement, SAR, emergency medical services, maritime patrol, military naval roles, armed reconnaissance, offshore, and passenger transport over years. Today, Leonardo serves more than 70 operators in Malaysia, which use over 240 helicopters, amassing more than 40,000 flight hours a year. Over the last ten years, the number of students trained locally has more than doubled, logging hundreds and amassed several thousands of simulation flight hours annually. This makes Malaysia one of the most active operational bases in the world, demonstrating the country’s strategic roles for highly skilled professional development.

Leonardo is now ready to expand its localized industrial activities in Malaysia with new and cutting-edge simulation and training capabilities, including additional Full-Flight Simulators and Interactive Trainers for helicopter operations. The company also plans to enhance or introduce MRO infrastructures for advanced blade repair, electronic system servicing and mission system integration, boosting Malaysia role as a global support hub for Leonardo.

“We’re proud to join forces with our established partner Weststar to respond to this important requirement set by the Malaysian Government to deliver greater rotorcraft capabilities to benefit national defence and security and the local communities,” said Gian Piero Cutillo, Managing Director of Leonardo Helicopters. “This latest initiative builds on the solid presence and the investments made over many years by Leonardo in the country, demonstrating we can be a reliable partner for key security and life-saving objectives, as well as the local economy and employment opportunities. Proximity, Innovation, and professional skills are key drivers of success. Thus, Malaysia continues to be a critical hub for us to serve the country and the greater region, and we’re committed to staying beside its Authorities to ensure our technology and services perform at their very best.”
 

About Weststar Aviation Services
Weststar Aviation Services is one of the global leaders in offshore helicopter transportation and a key player in the international energy aviation sector. Weststar operates a diverse fleet of state-of-the-art helicopters supporting critical missions across Asia, Africa, the Middle East, and Europe.
Driven by an unwavering commitment to safety, efficiency, and service excellence, Weststar delivers a comprehensive suite of aviation services, including offshore transportation for the oil and gas industry, defence aviation support, VIP helicopter charter services, medical evacuation (MEDEVAC) and emergency medical services (EMS), search and rescue (SAR) operations, and aerial utility services. These capabilities are supported by strategically located bases in major energy hubs, ensuring operational readiness and the highest safety standards at all times.
As the largest helicopter operator in Southeast Asia, Weststar Aviation Services continues to expand its global footprint and set new benchmarks in aviation innovation, reliability, and mission-critical performance.

For more information, please visit: www.weststar-aviation.aero

 

 

Photo: handshake during the ceremony between Syed Muhammad Azni Syed Azman, Executive Director of Weststar Aviation Services, and Stefano Villanti, Leonardo Helicopters SVP Sales, Marketing and Contracts (from left to right) </content></news>