<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<news><type>stampa</type><title>Aramco acquires C-27J Multi-Mission Aircraft to respond to firefighting and multi-mission requirements in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia</title><subtitle /><author /><date>Paris,  17 giugno 2025 13:24</date><content>Two C-27Js to be delivered starting from 2027
First order for the type in firefighter and multi-mission configuration from a civil operator and first order in the Middle East

 

The global presence of the Leonardo C-27J multi-mission tactical transport aircraft, with more than 270,000 flight hours worldwide, is set to grow with a new addition to the number of leading operators that have chosen and are using the aircraft to meet their demanding requirements. Leonardo will supply two C-27J multi-mission and firefighter aircraft to Aramco for cargo transport, firefighting, oil spill response, and medical evacuation operations in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. Mukamalah Aviation Company, a wholly owned subsidiary of Aramco, operating under the brand name “Aloula Aviation,” will operate the C-27Js and also act as service center for the type. Deliveries are expected starting from 2027.

Aloula Aviation is the 20th C-27J operator, and Leonardo records 95 aircraft ordered.
This latest achievement marks the first order from a civil operator for the C-27J in a multi-mission and firefighter configuration, following initial success in other markets as well as the entrance of this model in the Middle East. This provides further evidence of the platform’s versatility, uniquely combining cargo transport and firefighting and disaster response capabilities with a high level of customization. The program benefits from the continued investments into expanding the C-27J’s capabilities and technologies in terms of latest avionics and performance as well as tailored solutions for the task, allowing the type to meet emerging rigorous requirements from prime users.

The longstanding partnership between Leonardo and Aramco in the helicopter segment supporting the energy industry and rescue duties in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia will then be expanded to the fixed wing business. This is expected to further strengthen the role of the C-27J in the Middle East and Africa.

With the C-27J Next Generation Fire Fighter, Leonardo offers an innovative, high-tech solution for firefighting and disaster response, providing a turboprop airplane able to work with other fixed and rotary wings assets. What makes the C-27J unique is the second-generation MAFFS II (Modular Airborne Fire Fighting System), a "roll-on/roll off" transportable module that can be loaded and unloaded as required in only 90 minutes. The module consists of a 7,500-liter tank that can be refilled on the ground with water and retardant liquid in under 10 minutes. It also has a spray nozzle emerging through the left hatch of the fuselage. The C-27J Next Generation Fire Fighter is a real "ecosystem," in line with and supporting Leonardo’s sustainability plan, that is scalable and adaptable for different purposes. It is a modular tool capable of reducing costs by increasing the effectiveness of worldwide firefighting, and it includes disaster response capabilities.

The C-27J Fire Fighter is able to operate effectively even at low altitudes and in unfavorable weather conditions. Agile, manoeuvrable, and fast with a maximum cruising speed of 325 knots (602 Km/h) and equipped with cutting-edge digital avionics, it is able to perform Short Take Off and Landing (STOL) on short or semi-prepared runways near the sites of intervention; it can quickly reach and operate optimally where and when other firefighting vehicles traveling by air or land cannot operate, including isolated locations and places where water is scarce or the sea is too rough for "scooper" type aircraft. At an average speed of 130 knots (250 Km/h), a pressurized jet of water mixed with fire-retardant liquid can cover a large amount of ground with each drop. Its range can be adjusted, allowing the crew to adapt the profile of the mission to the specific conditions of each fire and the orography of the terrain. Moreover, the proposed solution is not limited to fighting fires – it is also able to be used in their prevention.

 

Note to Editors on Mukamalah Aviation Company

Mukamalah Aviation Company, a wholly owned subsidiary of Aramco, operating under the brand name “Aloula Aviation,” is the first civil aviation company in Saudi Arabia and second in the Middle East. It traces its origins to 1934, when the first aircraft was introduced by Aramco to support oil exploration operations in the Kingdom’s vast deserts. From its headquarters in Dammam, Saudi Arabia, Aloula operates 55 aircraft of different types. Enabling its operation, Aloula maintains its vast fleet in hangars across a number of key locations. In addition to operating and maintaining these aircraft, Aloula regularly serves different airports throughout Saudi Arabia, a number of which Aloula fully manages, serves, and operates, and more than 300 helipads, both on and offshore. The company is also an Authorized Service Center for Leonardo’s AW109 and AW139 helicopters.</content></news>